## ana enders



www.anaenders.com ana.enders@gmail.com www.github.com/anaenders

## profile

For some time now, I've been working closely with engineers, first as a Front-end Engineer and Designer, and more recently as a Tech Lead and Engineering Manager. I've spent the last 5 years working at a startup, where I joined as employee #3 (they've since raised several rounds and are at 135+ employees). I consider myself a generalist—shifting focus to whatever the business' needs are, while being able to perform various critical roles in a fast-paced environment. I split my day between managing ten people and being a team lead to our full-stack engineers. I establish code standards, perform code reviews, and I make sure team is a happy, highly functional, well-oiled machine.

education

2007 - 2008 | Parsons School of Design MFA Design + Technology

2001 - 2005 | Carnegie Mellon University BFA Music Performance, European Studies

likes

- · Interior design
- · Bea Arthur ice cream cones from Big Gay's
- · Home-made waffles
- Cuddles from my cat & dog while binge watching TV shows with Ian

dislikes

- IPAs
- · Winter and Summer
- Waking up early

experience

Engineering Manager - <u>The Muse</u> New York, NY - July 2012 - Present

Currently a team lead to full-stack engineers, establishing code standards, performing code reviews, coding, and managing. As a hiring manager, I've helped to recruit many of the engineers on the team. My strengths are in managing projects and people, and making sure everyone is happy and productive.

Freelance Font-end Developer - <u>Self Employed</u> San Francisco, CA - 07/2012 - 09/2011

Freelancing for old clients in need of front-end adjustments to their existing sites. Also worked on some logo and branding designs.

Clients: Tiffany & co. | Juice Generation | NewlyWish | Hackbright Academy

Front-end Developer - <u>Intersect NYC (a.k.a. Crown Partners a.k.a. Razorfish)</u>
New York, NY - 09/2008 - 09/2011 (3 years 1 month)

As a member of the development team, I worked closely with the designers, backend programmers, and software engineers in producing custom e-commerse sites and content management software.

Clients: Kenneth Cole | Liz Claiborne | Boast USA | Carlos Falchi | Chilewich | Thornton Tomasetti | Yigal Azrouël

